Barbara Rogasky Papers
© 2005 University of Connecticut
Barbara Rogasky Papers.
undated, 1988-1996.
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research enter.
Rogasky, Barbara.
1 linear foot.
MSS19980112
The collection contains research notes, correspondence, drafts, revisions and other materials pertaining to stories or books written by Ms. Rogasky.
Biography
Unknown.
Scope and Content
The collection contains research notes, correspondence, drafts, revisions and other materials pertaining to stories or books written by Barbara Rogasky.
Arrangement
Series I: Books ( undated, 1988-1996 )
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to children's literature and associated artwork. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Index Terms
This record series is indexed under the following controlled access subject terms.
Subjects:
Authors--American.
Document Types:
Correspondence.; Personal Papers.; Manuscripts.; Legal Records.
Occupations:
Author.
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Acquisition Information
The collection was donated by Ms. Rogasky in June 1998.
Detailed Description
- Series I: Books, undated, 1988-1996
  - The Golem
    - Contract, 1990 (Box 1:, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1996 (Box 1:, Folder 2)
    - Clippings, undated (Box 1:, Folder 3)
    - Notes, undated (Box 1:, Folder 4)
    - Earliest versions, undated (Box 1:, Folder 5)
    - Manuscript draft, undated (Box 1:, Folder 6)
    - Chapter revisions
      - The Lion, undated (Box 1:, Folder 7)
      - The Golem is created, undated (Box 1:, Folder 8)
      - Too much of a good thing, undated (Box 1:, Folder 9)
      - Red Beards, undated (Box 1:, Folder 10)
      - The Butcher, undated (Box 1:, Folder 11)
      - The Ruin, undated (Box 1:, Folder 12)
      - The Priest, undated (Box 1:, Folder 13)
      - Fish and Apples, undated (Box 1:, Folder 14)
      - A Bad exchange, undated (Box 1:, Folder 15)
      - The Attack, undated (Box 1:, Folder 16)
      - The Five Sided Palace, undated (Box 1:, Folder 17)
      - Golem Runs Amok, undated (Box 1:, Folder 18)
    - Inserts, undated (Box 1:, Folder 19)
    - Mss revisions not used, undated (Box 1:, Folder 20)
    - Mss revised chapters 1-10, 1993 (Box 1:, Folder 21)
    - Mss draft, 1993 (Box 1:, Folder 22)
    - Chapters 1-10, 1993 (Box 1:, Folder 23)
    - Author's Note, 1994 (Box 1:, Folder 24)
    - Mss revised, 1994 (Box 1:, Folder 25)
    - All revisions except afterword and author's note, 1995 (Box 1:, Folder 26)
    - Proof, 1996 (Box 2:, Folder 27)
  - Light and Shadow
    - Correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 2:, Folder 28)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:, Folder 29)
  - On the Wings of Peace (Japanese Internment)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1994 (Box 2:, Folder 30)
    - “A Shameful Chapter”, undated (Box 2:, Folder 31)
    - On the Wings of Peace, 1994 (Box 2:, Folder 32-33)
  - Winter Poems
    - Foreward first draft, 1991 (Box 2:, Folder 34)
    - Manuscript, undated (Box 2:, Folder 35)
    - Final Draft, 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 36)
    - Revision #1, 1993 (Box 2:, Folder 37)
    - Copy edited manuscript, undated (Box 2:, Folder 38)
    - Correspondence, 1988-1996 (Box 2:, Folder 39)
    - Permissions, 1991-1994 (Box 2:, Folder 40)
    - Poems and sources, undated (Box 2:, Folder 41)
    - Rejected poems, undated (Box 2:, Folder 42)